hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
in this session we are going to talk
about how we can create Trend charts out
of our Tosca execution lists
so once you execute your automated test
cases from your execution list you can
create different types of trend charts
which could be used for reporting
purpose
so to enable this particular feature we
need to go to our project
then go to options
and there you will find a option called
View
in that view you will find an option to
enable Trend charts now if this is not
enabled go ahead and enable this and
then click on OK
once you enable this and when you come
to an execution list folder then you
will find a trend chart option or a tab
which will be displayed behind your
details and test configuration
now this will be available for any
particular folder or execution list
now if you go into this trend chart you
will see there is a trend chart for your
executions
and by default it is uh set to Stacked
bar chart
but you can also change this particular
View
now what is displayed in the strength
chart
so in the y-axis it indicates what you
have executed okay so the number of test
cases which are executed
and then in the x-axis it displays the
execution list in a specified time
interval so whatever is chosen as the
time interval it will display the
results uh based on that currently it is
set to months okay so every month
whatever you have executed it is showing
the results for that now if you hover
over the results you will see that it
will show you the time interval it will
show you how many have passed how many
are field and how many of them were no
results
now how you can change the view of this
particular chart so there are several
options as I said by default it is set
to Stacked bar
you can also select the bar option or
the line option or there are also some
3D options which are available so there
are lots of options as you can see here
and you can choose any of these charts
uh based on your requirement
then there is the timeline okay as I
said it is set to months currently but
it can be set to years weeks days or
hours now depending on your reporting
requirements you can change this okay
as I said it is set to months right now
I can set it to years and then weeks or
days okay
also you can zoom in and zoom out of
this particular chart as you can see I
can zoom into just one day or I can zoom
out and it will show me all the days uh
in the month or in the last 30 days
right
so this is a pretty configurable as you
can see you can also reset this
particular diagram to the default view
what you had set okay and then
um this is the default view when you
come into a trend chart okay
so as I said this could be useful if you
want it for your reporting purpose also
if you have created a trend chart as I
showed earlier that is the print view
through which you can easily uh save
this okay
Trend chart in any format you like Okay
so
now um I can export this document as a
PDF file as the HTML file a docx XLS
right so any particular file you want
you could easily export this
okay so you can save this in HTML format
and then you can go ahead and you can
look at this HTML document you have
saved okay
so let's call it Trend chart
and let's save this and let's open the
file
and you will see it will open in your
browser this particular Trend chart
so you can easily configure this as I
showed you and you can easily save it in
any different format for reporting
purpose
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video